<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cicd on 丸子有记</title><link>/tags/cicd/</link><description>Recent content in cicd on 丸子有记</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</managingEditor><webMaster>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</webMaster><copyright>丸子有记</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:22:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cicd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started with Github Actions</title><link>/post/cicd-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-github-actions/</guid><description>What is Github Action? GitHub Actions is a continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) platform that lets you automate your build, test, and deployment processes. You can create workflows to build and test every pull request to your repository, or deploy merged pull requests to production. GitHub Actions is more than just DevOps; it lets you run workflows when other events happen in your repository. For example, you can run</description></item><item><title>Github Actions automatically deploys hugo to Github Pages</title><link>/post/cicd-github-actions-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-github-actions-hugo/</guid><description>Preface I recently planned to upgrade the theme of my blog. Since I was playing around with Github Actions, I planned to use it to implement CICD. After writing and submitting the article, the static files generated by hugo will be automatically deployed to Github pages, Netlify, Vercel, Cloud flare Pages and other third-party platforms. Today, I will record the automatic deployment process of Github pages, which will save a</description></item><item><title>Argocd deployment appears: no space left on device</title><link>/post/kubernetes-error-no-space-left-on-device/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 10:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-error-no-space-left-on-device/</guid><description>Failure phenomenon In the morning, several business applications were deployed through argocd. After deploying 2, the third-party deployment failed. The same configuration, different knowledge clusters, how could such a problem occur? So I checked the log, as follows: Copy 1 2 3 Warning Failed 1m kubelet, 172.16.25.13 Error: Error response from daemon: error creating overlay mount to /var/lib/docker/overlay2/ba37165607862efb350093e5e287207e2547759fd81dc4e5e356a86ac5e28324-init/merged: no space left on device Warning Failed 1m kubelet, 172.16.25.13 Error: Error</description></item></channel></rss>