<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aliyun on 丸子有记</title><link>/tags/aliyun/</link><description>Recent content in aliyun on 丸子有记</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</managingEditor><webMaster>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</webMaster><copyright>丸子有记</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 18:10:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/aliyun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Alibaba Cloud's open source solution to enable multiple people to use a single GPU</title><link>/post/kubernetes-aliyun-gpushare-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 18:10:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-aliyun-gpushare-deploy/</guid><description>Recently, a new AI project was launched, which mainly provides AI online experiments for universities. The project also purchased a GPU server, but there is only one Nvidia Tesla T4 card, which needs to support multiple students to do experiments online at the same time. The online experiment system is currently running on Kubernetes, so it is necessary to consider GPU sharing in the k8s environment. Alibaba Cloud GPU card</description></item><item><title>Automatically renew a free SSL certificate for your blog</title><link>/post/tools-ssl-renew-acme/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 16:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/tools-ssl-renew-acme/</guid><description>Background If you have a website or an independent blog, you need to care about the expiration of your website&amp;rsquo;s SSL certificate every year. Recently, the wnote.com certificate is about to expire; Applying for an SSL certificate allows the website to support https access. There are free and paid ones on the market; For free certificates, domestic mainstream cloud vendors such as Alibaba, Tencent, ucloud and other platforms have free</description></item><item><title>Solve nginx file upload restrictions and 504 gateway timeout under k8s</title><link>/post/kubernetes-nginx-ingress-504/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-nginx-ingress-504/</guid><description>Recently, there are two problems that need to be solved when using k8s clusters for business. Here are some records: 1M limit for uploading files on the front-end page 504 timeout occurs when the front-end page sends a POST request to the back-end The main solution to the first problem: the default upload size of nginx is 1M, and the following content is added to the http, server, location area</description></item><item><title>Alibaba Cloud ACK supports both public and private SLB</title><link>/post/kubernetes-aliyun-ingress-slb-intranet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-aliyun-ingress-slb-intranet/</guid><description>1. Background There is an ACK cluster Successfully deployed Nginx ingress controller and bound to the public network SLB Note: The Kubernetes cluster created through the Alibaba Cloud Container Service Management Console will automatically deploy a set of Nginx Ingress Controllers during initialization, which is mounted on the public network SLB instance by default. 2. Configuration 1. Create an intranet LB Alibaba Cloud Console, create an intranet SLB and bind</description></item><item><title>Alibaba Cloud Shared GPU Solution Test</title><link>/post/kubernetes-gpushare-aliyun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 14:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-gpushare-aliyun/</guid><description>1. Deploy GPU sharing plug-in in k8s Before deployment, you need to ensure that nvidia-driver and nvidia-docker are installed on the k8s node, and the default runtime of docker is set to nvidia Copy 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 # cat /etc/docker/daemon.json { &amp;#34;runtimes&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;nvidia&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;path&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;/usr/bin/nvidia-container-runtime&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;runtimeArgs&amp;#34;: [] } }, &amp;#34;default-runtime&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;nvidia&amp;#34;, } 1. Install gpushare-device-plugin in helm Copy 1 2 3</description></item><item><title>Alibaba Cloud PrivateZone+Bind9+Dnsmasq implements internal DNS</title><link>/post/linux-dns-privatezone-bind9-dnsmasq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/linux-dns-privatezone-bind9-dnsmasq/</guid><description>Requirements: Alibaba Cloud cluster can resolve internal domain names Office network resolves internal domain names + office network Internet resolution Solution: For the first problem, use Alibaba Cloud PrivateZone for resolution For the second problem, configure the internal domain name zone in PrivateZone, and then synchronize it to the office network bind9 server through Alibaba Cloud synchronization tool; For the office network DNS resolution entry, use Dnsmasq to process, and</description></item><item><title>Terraform automatically creates ECS</title><link>/post/devops-terraform-create-aliyun-ecs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/devops-terraform-create-aliyun-ecs/</guid><description>Quickly create an Alibaba Cloud ECS host Specify the terraform version Here we specify the Alibaba Cloud provider version information and set the terraform version requirements Copy 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 # mkdir aliyun-ecs-one &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd aliyun-ecs-one # touch versions.tf # vim versions.tf terraform { required_providers { alicloud = { source = &amp;#34;aliyun/alicloud&amp;#34; version = &amp;#34;1.115.1&amp;#34; } } required_version = &amp;#34;&amp;gt;=</description></item><item><title>Detailed explanation of terraform installation and commands</title><link>/post/devops-terraform-command-detail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/devops-terraform-command-detail/</guid><description>Install Terraform Mac system installation Copy 1 2 brew tap hashicorp/tap brew install hashicorp/tap/terraform Linux system installation Ubuntu installation Copy 1 2 3 curl -fsSL https://apt.releases.hashicorp.com/gpg | sudo apt-key add - sudo apt-add-repository &amp;#34;deb [arch=amd64] https://apt.releases.hashicorp.com $(lsb_release -cs) main&amp;#34; sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get install terraform CentOS system Copy 1 2 3 sudo yum install -y yum-utils sudo yum-config-manager --add-repo https://rpm.releases.hashicorp.com/RHEL/hashicorp.repo sudo yum -y install terraform Verify installation Copy</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Terraform, an automated orchestration tool</title><link>/post/devops-terraform-about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/devops-terraform-about/</guid><description>What is Terraform? ： Terraform is an open source resource orchestration tool launched by HashiCorp around 2014. Currently, almost all mainstream cloud service providers support Terraform, including Alibaba Cloud, Tencent Cloud, Huawei Cloud, AWS, Azure, Baidu Cloud, etc. Many companies currently build their own infrastructure based on terraform. Background: In the traditional operation and maintenance model, the launch of a business requires preparation stages such as equipment procurement, machine installation,</description></item></channel></rss>