<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>argocd on 丸子有记</title><link>/tags/argocd/</link><description>Recent content in argocd on 丸子有记</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</managingEditor><webMaster>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</webMaster><copyright>丸子有记</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 15:22:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/argocd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ArgoCD+Jenkins Pipeline Automated Application Deployment</title><link>/post/cicd-argocd-jenkins-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 15:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-argocd-jenkins-pipeline/</guid><description>Create helm repository First, create a basic Helm template repository: Copy 1 helm create template . For actual deployment, you need to customize your own helm template according to your business. I will directly use our internal custom universal template for quick deployment; you can also refer to the helm chart maintained by bitnami (https://github.com/bitnami/charts/tree/master/bitnami) Jenkins credential configuration argocd token information Configure Jenkins pipeline writing Here we take the gotest</description></item><item><title>Argocd deployment appears: no space left on device</title><link>/post/kubernetes-error-no-space-left-on-device/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 10:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-error-no-space-left-on-device/</guid><description>Failure phenomenon In the morning, several business applications were deployed through argocd. After deploying 2, the third-party deployment failed. The same configuration, different knowledge clusters, how could such a problem occur? So I checked the log, as follows: Copy 1 2 3 Warning Failed 1m kubelet, 172.16.25.13 Error: Error response from daemon: error creating overlay mount to /var/lib/docker/overlay2/ba37165607862efb350093e5e287207e2547759fd81dc4e5e356a86ac5e28324-init/merged: no space left on device Warning Failed 1m kubelet, 172.16.25.13 Error: Error</description></item><item><title>ArgoCD adds multi-cluster</title><link>/post/cicd-argocd-add-clusters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 15:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-argocd-add-clusters/</guid><description>Generate argocd management user token Log in to the dashboard, settings&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;Accounts&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;admin&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;Generate New After generating, please record the token information, similar to the following: Copy 1 fyJhbGciOiJ3UzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJqdGkiOiI2OWI0M2M0Mi01MmZiLTRlZmItODIxOC0yOWU3NGM5MWI0NDIiLCJpYXQiOjE1OTUzMTEx3zQsImlzcyI6ImFyZ29jZCIsIm5iZiI6MTU5NTMxMTE3NCwic3ViIjoib3duZXIifQ.9u4XzArEeaz7G2Q2TWusnTkakEmq9BYDAUHr3dC6wG5 Configure argocd config For argocd with https authentication enabled, it is useless when adding a cluster. You need to log in to the server-side POD for configuration, as follows: Copy 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 #</description></item><item><title>ArgoCD installation and deployment</title><link>/post/cicd-argocd-install-in-k8s/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 15:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-argocd-install-in-k8s/</guid><description>Installation and deployment ArgoCD is very easy to deploy. Install the official deployment method (HA mode: Copy 1 2 kubectl create namespace argocd kubectl apply -n argocd -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/argoproj/argo-cd/v1.5.2/manifests/ha/install.yaml You can adjust the deployment file as needed. After the pod is successfully started Copy 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 # kubectl -n</description></item></channel></rss>