<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on 丸子有记</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on 丸子有记</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</managingEditor><webMaster>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</webMaster><copyright>丸子有记</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:22:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Github Actions automatically deploys hugo to Github Pages</title><link>/post/cicd-github-actions-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-github-actions-hugo/</guid><description>Preface I recently planned to upgrade the theme of my blog. Since I was playing around with Github Actions, I planned to use it to implement CICD. After writing and submitting the article, the static files generated by hugo will be automatically deployed to Github pages, Netlify, Vercel, Cloud flare Pages and other third-party platforms. Today, I will record the automatic deployment process of Github pages, which will save a</description></item><item><title>Summary of CKA Examination Experience in 2024</title><link>/post/kubernetes-cka-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 10:10:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-cka-2024/</guid><description>I have wanted to take a cloud native &amp;amp; k8s related certificate for a long time. The sooner the better. I have been postponing it until this year due to work reasons. I have seen its price increase twice (it hurts a little bit to say this). Recently, I finally had time to spare a week to prepare for the exam. Since I have been using kubernetes in my work</description></item><item><title>Open source Waf security protection solution</title><link>/post/tools-safeline-waf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 16:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/tools-safeline-waf/</guid><description>After adding CDN to the website recently, there are always a lot of junk requests inexplicably in the early morning, some of which are scans, some are large model UserAgents, and some are black spiders. In order to save CDN costs and prevent various injection attacks, I started to investigate open source Waf solutions (my own small broken site is enough). If it is used by an enterprise, it is</description></item><item><title>Use ollama and open-webui to experience open source big models</title><link>/post/ai-ollama-open-webui/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 18:10:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/ai-ollama-open-webui/</guid><description>It has been more than a year since the use of large models. From the initial chatgbt3.5/4 to the current domestic large models, open source large models are becoming more and more powerful, such as Llama, SD, etc. Today, I will introduce two tools that have been used for a long time, ollama and open-webui. Ollama Ollama is an open source deep learning framework designed for easy deployment and operation</description></item><item><title>Python script to generate a sitemap</title><link>/post/python-generate-sitemap/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 10:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/python-generate-sitemap/</guid><description>I was recently helping a friend research a CMS site group and found that the CMS did not have a sitemap function. Python3 was already installed on the server, so I could only temporarily generate one using a script. I’ll record it here. Script content: Copy 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21</description></item><item><title>A powerful tool for operating Baidu Cloud Disk under Linux</title><link>/post/tools-bypy-baiduyunpan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 16:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/tools-bypy-baiduyunpan/</guid><description>Recently, I have been deploying private SAAS products on the customer side. Since the customer&amp;rsquo;s on-site network cannot access the Internet, the data can only be transferred through the Linux jump server. In addition to the k8s offline deployment program and image, there are also hundreds of GB of video data that have been cut, so it can only be transferred through Baidu Cloud Disk. Imagine whether it is possible</description></item><item><title>An open source Windows package management tool</title><link>/post/tools-scoop-windows-brew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 16:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/tools-scoop-windows-brew/</guid><description>Since I have been using Mac for work and am used to the convenience of installing software packages with brew on Mac, I recently installed Windows on my company computer. I want to try it out. How can I install software packages as smoothly as on MAC? Of course, the protagonist I recommend today is Scoop. Scoop is an open source project that mainly installs Windows software packages through commands.</description></item><item><title>Using Alibaba Cloud's open source solution to enable multiple people to use a single GPU</title><link>/post/kubernetes-aliyun-gpushare-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 18:10:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-aliyun-gpushare-deploy/</guid><description>Recently, a new AI project was launched, which mainly provides AI online experiments for universities. The project also purchased a GPU server, but there is only one Nvidia Tesla T4 card, which needs to support multiple students to do experiments online at the same time. The online experiment system is currently running on Kubernetes, so it is necessary to consider GPU sharing in the k8s environment. Alibaba Cloud GPU card</description></item><item><title>Golang pointer detailed explanation</title><link>/post/golang-note-pointer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 18:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/golang-note-pointer/</guid><description>What is a pointer? In Go, a pointer is a variable that stores the memory address of another variable. Therefore, a pointer variable points to the memory address of another variable, not the variable itself. When declaring a pointer variable, you need to add * before the variable name to indicate that it is a pointer variable, for example: Copy 1 var p *int This means that a pointer named</description></item><item><title>Kind builds a lightweight kubernetes cluster</title><link>/post/kubernetes-kind-build-clusters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 18:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-kind-build-clusters/</guid><description>I was reviewing Golang recently and wrote a web application. After running it locally, I wanted to test it in a k8s cluster. Due to the machine configuration, it was still a bit difficult to build a complete k8s cluster. I remember that a friend said that k8s can also be run in docker, so I tried it. Today&amp;rsquo;s protagonist is kind, so what is kind? What can kind be</description></item><item><title>Jenkins Agent integrates docker and kubectl tools</title><link>/post/cicd-jenkins-agent-docker-kubectl-helm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 18:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-jenkins-agent-docker-kubectl-helm/</guid><description>When we build Jenkins, the official jenkins-agent does not have the tools we use, such as helm, kubectl, curl, argocd, etc., so we need to integrate them. Note that the official image names have changed: jenkins/agent image, originally named jenkins/slave, renamed to jenkins/agent from 4.3-2 jenkins/inbound-agent image: originally named jenkins/jnlp-slave, renamed to jenkins/inbound-agent from 4.3-2 Dockerfile Copy 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 FROM jenkins/inbound-agent:4.11-1-alpine-jdk11 USER</description></item><item><title>Jenkins Workspace and Maven cache local persistent storage</title><link>/post/cicd-jenkins-localstorage-workspace-maven/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 16:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-jenkins-localstorage-workspace-maven/</guid><description>Create local storage Since this is a test cluster, we can directly use local volume storage here; Since the user running in the jenkins server here is jenkins, and the uid of jenkins is 1000, we need to grant /opt/jenkins_agent/ and /opt/jenkins_maven/ permissions to jenkins in advance on node1 Copy 1 2 chown 1000.1000 -R /opt/jenkins_agent -R chown 1000.1000 -R /opt/jenkins_maven/ -R Local storage: agent-pv-pvc.yaml Copy 1 2 3 4</description></item><item><title>Golang basic programming</title><link>/post/golang-note-datatype-struct/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 18:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/golang-note-datatype-struct/</guid><description>1. Basic knowledge 1. Basic data types Value type: Copy 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 bool (length 1Byte or 1 byte) byte (1 byte, uint8 alias) rune (4 bytes, int32 alias, -231~231) int (32 or 64, length 4 or 8 bytes) int8 (length 1 byte), int16 (length 2 bytes), int32 (length 4 bytes), int64 (length 8 bytes) uint (32 or 64, length 4</description></item><item><title>Deploy Jenkins in kubernetes environment</title><link>/post/cicd-jenkins-in-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 16:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/cicd-jenkins-in-kubernetes/</guid><description>1. Install and deploy Jenkins 1. Manual installation Manual installation is very simple. Just prepare the yaml configuration in advance. The content of all CICD resources jenkins-install.yaml is as follows: Copy 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 apiVersion: v1 kind: PersistentVolume metadata: name: jenkins-pv spec: storageClassName: local</description></item><item><title>Delve version is too low to be compatible with Goland</title><link>/post/tools-goland-delve-err/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 16:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/tools-goland-delve-err/</guid><description>Problem When debugging code in Goland recently, the following error is always reported: Copy 1 WARNING: undefined behavior - version of Delve is too old for Go version 1.19.3 (maximum supported version 1.18) Solution The problem probably means that the Delve version is too low and cannot meet the current Golang version Update delve. Since I use brew to install it here, the default official website installation document does not</description></item><item><title>Automatically renew a free SSL certificate for your blog</title><link>/post/tools-ssl-renew-acme/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 16:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/tools-ssl-renew-acme/</guid><description>Background If you have a website or an independent blog, you need to care about the expiration of your website&amp;rsquo;s SSL certificate every year. Recently, the wnote.com certificate is about to expire; Applying for an SSL certificate allows the website to support https access. There are free and paid ones on the market; For free certificates, domestic mainstream cloud vendors such as Alibaba, Tencent, ucloud and other platforms have free</description></item><item><title>Recommend a Markdown book writing tool, which is said to be a GitBook alternative</title><link>/post/tools-mdbook-write-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/tools-mdbook-write-books/</guid><description>Introduction to mdBook mdBook is a command-line tool written in Rust and used to create books in Markdown. It is ideal for creating product or API documentation, tutorials, course materials, or any presentation that needs to be concise, easy to navigate, and customizable. The functionality is similar to Gitbook, and the biggest advantage is speed. Lightweight, Markdown syntax Search, integrated search function Syntax highlighting, syntax highlighting Multiple themes, Theme custom</description></item><item><title>Summary and thoughts on CDN</title><link>/post/linux-cdn-cloud-aliyun-cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 12:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/linux-cdn-cloud-aliyun-cloudfront/</guid><description>The COVID-19 epidemic has repeatedly affected daily life and work. I have had too many things happen in the past six months. My family members are seriously ill and my grandmother has passed away. I have a lot of things to do, so I have stopped updating my blog for half a year. Facing the economic downturn, layoffs have begun in all walks of life, and many companies have begun</description></item><item><title>Solve nginx file upload restrictions and 504 gateway timeout under k8s</title><link>/post/kubernetes-nginx-ingress-504/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-nginx-ingress-504/</guid><description>Recently, there are two problems that need to be solved when using k8s clusters for business. Here are some records: 1M limit for uploading files on the front-end page 504 timeout occurs when the front-end page sends a POST request to the back-end The main solution to the first problem: the default upload size of nginx is 1M, and the following content is added to the http, server, location area</description></item><item><title>Alibaba Cloud ACK supports both public and private SLB</title><link>/post/kubernetes-aliyun-ingress-slb-intranet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 17:22:42 +0800</pubDate><author>wzdushu@gmail.com (wanzi)</author><guid>/post/kubernetes-aliyun-ingress-slb-intranet/</guid><description>1. Background There is an ACK cluster Successfully deployed Nginx ingress controller and bound to the public network SLB Note: The Kubernetes cluster created through the Alibaba Cloud Container Service Management Console will automatically deploy a set of Nginx Ingress Controllers during initialization, which is mounted on the public network SLB instance by default. 2. Configuration 1. Create an intranet LB Alibaba Cloud Console, create an intranet SLB and bind</description></item></channel></rss>